<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[SpaceTraveler]]></title>
  <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-07T14:42:46+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SpaceTraveler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.2 - Travel Guidelines.]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/07/0-dot-0-0-dot-2-travel-guidelines/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-07T10:51:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/07/0-dot-0-0-dot-2-travel-guidelines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thoughts on packing a bag.
Preparations are a highly speculative undertaking. Being well-prepared is more of an easy mindset and less of a list of items with checkmarks behind them.</p>

<p>Fortunately bags come with physical constraints, space and subsequently weight is limited by the volume of their model. It is helpful to remind yourself that the person packing the bag is likely the one carrying it too.
I&rsquo;m looking at journeys of fellow travelers for hints on things that promise to be massively useful. Undoubtedly, the first item I&rsquo;m throwing into my own backpack is a towel.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.1 - Navigating the Curious Ruby Orbit.]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/06/11/navigating-the-curious-ruby-orbit/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-11T13:35:15+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/06/11/navigating-the-curious-ruby-orbit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This space tells of a particular community that evolved from gravity, more precisely <i>Ruby Gravity</i>. According to the SpaceTraveler’s Encyclopedia Ruby Gravity is defined as a natural phenomenon by which all those who affiliate with the Ruby programming language meet one another. Beware, it may result in spirited conversations, fruitful collaboration and sometimes genuine friendships.</p>

<p>The SpaceTraveler drifts through the well-known as well as peripheral edges of this community, to find essential and/ or creative applications of the language, while purposely leaving a visible trace.
As with most stories, this adventure too begins with one small step *thdwuuf</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
