<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[SpaceTraveler]]></title>
  <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-15T12:28:52+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SpaceTraveler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.3 - RubyNation DC 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/08/rubyissue-s/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/08/rubyissue-s</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some giant leaps begin with one small step. Others begin with covering 6,706 km (i.e. 4166.92 miles), while sitting in a chair in the sky above the North Atlantic Ocean.</p>

<p><img src="images/travel/washington.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean" width="400px" height="400px"></p>

<p>On June 7th 2015 the SpaceTraveler crew and I left our base in Berlin and headed for the US of A.
The crew was intrigued to meet the <a href="www.meetup.com/NYC-rb/">Ruby user group in New York City</a> and attend <a href="http://www.rubynation.org/">RubyNation</a> in Washington DC.
Switching continents plus time zones to mingle with the programmer community at a regional conference seems quite some trouble to take on. That&rsquo;s probably true.</br></p>

<p>However, the mission of the SpaceTraveler is to explore and understand the ecosystem of the Ruby programming language – which we refer to as the <em>Ruby Orbit</em> – and share findings.
Meeting and getting to know different contributors, actors and visitors as well as investigating contemporary fields of interests, issues and questions is essential in this regard.</p>

<p>If you ask me about the success of this particular trip, I don&rsquo;t have a tool to measure that (just yet). What I do have are a growing number of strategies that indicate how to best approach the SpaceTraveler&rsquo;s mission. One of them I learned from philosopher, writer and designer John Thackara and his talk <a href="http://www.doorsofperception.com/learning-institutions/presence-and-encounter-how-we-meet-is-as-important-as-why/">How we meet is as important as why</a>. The following paragraph is taken from his write-up: </br></p>

<p>&ldquo;In his book I and Thou in 1923, the philosopher and theologian Martin Buber counseled that &lsquo;All knowledge is dialogic&rsquo;  – but he did not just advocate talk. Community and connection are not just about words, he said;  they’re about encounter, and presence.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A thought that does not only justify, but strongly recommends we cross an ocean – or possibly an entire galaxy – in order to meet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.2 - *thdwuuf]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/07/0-dot-0-0-dot-2-travel-guidelines/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-07T10:51:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/07/0-dot-0-0-dot-2-travel-guidelines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kon’nichi wa and welcome from the Ruby Orbit.</br>
By the by, *thdwuuf is an Onomatopoeia – a written sound – that describes the noise any kind of boots creates when walking on sand.</p>

<p>Running through my mission checklist it says: Leave a visible trace!</br>
In this regard, you may have noticed the shiny red element greeting you at the top of my Logbook.
It resembles the imprint of my boots:</p>

<p><img src="images/velement/bootsteps.png" alt="SpaceTraveler" width="200px" height="200px"></p>

<p>Neat, right?
The soles sport a pattern made from gemstones of different shapes and sizes – proper RubyBoots!</br>
Wherever Ruby gravity takes me, these prints will be left in space. In this way you are able to track my projects or undertakings and instantly know they are part of this SpaceTraveler Mission.</p>

<p>Why bootsteps? I was inspired by the following historic event: </br>
the Apollo 11 spaceflight. More precisely the trace Neil Armstrong left behind on the Moon on July 21 at 02:56 UTC.</p>

<p><img src="images/velement/261252main_21_firstfootprint_946-710.jpg" alt="Footprints on the moon" width="400px" height="400px"></br>
<a href="http://www.nasa.gov/50th/favpic/moonFootprint.html">Image Source</a></p>

<p>Following I&rsquo;m going to take you on a visual stroll throught the early development of this visual element as well as its iterations.</p>

<p><img src="images/velement/element_dev.jpg" alt="Element development" height="700px"></br></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.1 - Navigating the Curious Ruby Orbit.]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/06/11/navigating-the-curious-ruby-orbit/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-11T13:35:15+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/06/11/navigating-the-curious-ruby-orbit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This space tells of a particular community that evolved from gravity, more precisely <i>Ruby Gravity</i>. According to the SpaceTraveler’s Encyclopedia Ruby Gravity is defined as a natural phenomenon by which all those who affiliate with the Ruby programming language meet one another. Beware, it may result in spirited conversations, fruitful collaboration and sometimes genuine friendships.</p>

<p>The SpaceTraveler drifts through the well-known as well as peripheral edges of this community, to find essential and/ or creative applications of the language, while purposely leaving a visible trace.
As with most stories, this adventure too begins with one small step *thdwuuf</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
