<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[SpaceTraveler]]></title>
  <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-26T14:38:00+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[SpaceTraveler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.6 - BrightonRuby 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/22/brightonruby-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-22T12:24:12+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/22/brightonruby-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Spacetraveler&rsquo;s Robin and Sonja are expected to return to base later this evening – after crossing a substantially shorter distance this time around.</br>
Nevertheless, lounging with the mostly British Ruby community in Brighton was highly animating and had some extra thrill in store.</p>

<p>On a sidenote, I wish I had known that we would be moving that much closer towards the sun. Contrary to all expectations, packing sunscreen for UK travels is advisable. 20+ at least.</p>

<p><img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/travel/brighton.jpg" alt="Brighton Pier"></br></p>

<p>Apart from sizzling rays of sun, it was host Andy Croll&rsquo;s positive energy that ignited BrightonRuby&rsquo;s incredibly welcoming atmosphere. Thus, I was pleasantly excited to give a short and sweet Lightning talk about <a href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/16/rubyissue-s/">RubyIssue(s)</a> on stage.</p>

<p>Standing in line for microphone and spotlight amongst wonderful fellow speakers is a remarkable and equally humbling experience.
Amongst others, <a href="https://twitter.com/binaryberry">Tatiana Soukiassian</a> made an engaging case for the importance to create a fruitful work environment for Junior Developers. <a href="https://twitter.com/robmil">Rob Miller&rsquo;s</a> stage debut on the topic of small data munging burst with all kinds of British smartness.</br>
Asking the question why a majority of women leave &lsquo;tech&rsquo; work environments provides a different perspective on this particular diversity issue. <a href="https://twitter.com/KinseyAnnDurham">Kinsey Durham</a> investigated exactly that question and shared her findings.</br>
Lastly, <a href="https://twitter.com/avdi">Avdi Grimm</a> maneuvered the audience through an intriguing,  somewhat challenging body of thought and carved out a potential future outlook for the Ruby language.</p>

<p><img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/RubyIssues/issues_presentation.jpg" alt="RubyIssue(s)"></br>
Watch this space for the link to all recordings from the day.</br>
Also, add a reminder for BrightonRuby 2016 to your calendar.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.5 - RubyIssue(s)]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/16/rubyissue-s/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-16T10:55:31+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/16/rubyissue-s</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Keep up, keep up! SpaceTraveler entered a wormhole.
A word of caution:<br>
This particular wormhole presents a shortcut across the Ruby Orbit into the space of open source work.
It brings with it the thrill of sudden velocity, high work mania and inspiring contact with exotic matter.</p>

<p><img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/RubyIssues/issues_logo_blck.png" alt="RubyIssue(s)"></p>

<p>Follow <a href="https://rubyissues.ongoodbits.com">RubyIssue(s)</a> to stay in the loop.</p>

<p>Upon subscription you will receive a curated collection of current issues related to significant Ruby projects – on a bi-monthly basis. No SPAM, double-promise.</p>

<p>Our ambition is to connect members of the Ruby community with matching projects as well as each other.
Providing an entry point to the open source space for developers of all levels and from various backgrounds. We approach this by establishing a foundation for enjoyable interaction, e.g. assess conditions for contributions and necessary skill levels as well as contacting project maintainers in advance.</p>

<p>The crew is always curious for feedback and to speak about issue(s).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.4 - BootStep Experiments]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/15/bootstep-experiments/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-15T10:30:52+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/15/bootstep-experiments</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier I introduced BootSteps as the visual element that SpaceTraveler leaves behind.
So far it only lived in a digital environment. In order to change that I explored a way to create a physical prototype.
Obviously, starting with a digital mock-up yet again.</br>
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/00_mockup.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean"></p>

<p>Create a blind, it will be used to shape the silicone mold.</br>
Always use a sharp scalpel when cutting stuff.</br>
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/01_cut.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean">
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/02_glue.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean"></p>

<p>Combine the blue with the white dough in equal shares. Do not eat.</br>
Knead until the color of the material is even. You have five minutes to bring it into your desired shape, then the silicone mold will stay as is.</br>
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/03_silicon.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean">
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/04_blinds.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean"></p>

<p>I decided on Ruby red cask resin for the final imprint.
Again, do not eat. Protective gloves are furthermore advisable.</br>
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/05_harz.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean"></p>

<p>Mix two parts resin to one part of hardener.</br>
Stir with a wooden stick.</br>
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/06_mix.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean"></p>

<p>Wait for eventual bubbles of trapped air to travel to the surface.</br>
Pour the mixture into your silicone mold. All done.</br>
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/07_fill.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean"></p>

<p>Patiently wait for 24h.</br>
Voila. The hardened resin is ready to be released from the mold.</br>
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/08_form.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean"></p>

<p>While the finished piece features a fine shiny surface, the opposite side does not fulfill my expectations. It is rough and matt. Very DIY.</br>
Polishing might improve its appearance, but for now I will resort to good old photo filters. Digital magic.</br>
<img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/swag/09_scene.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.3 - RubyNation DC 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/08/rubynation2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/08/rubynation2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some giant leaps begin with one small step. Others begin with covering 6,706 km (i.e. 4166.92 miles), while sitting in a chair in the sky above the North Atlantic Ocean.</p>

<p><img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/travel/washington.jpg" alt="Over the North Atlantic Ocean"></p>

<p>On June 7th 2015 the SpaceTraveler crew and I left our base in Berlin and headed for the US of A.
The crew was intrigued to meet the <a href="www.meetup.com/NYC-rb/">Ruby user group in New York City</a> and attend <a href="http://www.rubynation.org/">RubyNation</a> in Washington DC.
Switching continents plus time zones to mingle with the programmer community at a regional conference seems quite some trouble to take on. That&rsquo;s probably true.</br></p>

<p>However, the mission of the SpaceTraveler is to explore and understand the ecosystem of the Ruby programming language – which we refer to as the <em>Ruby Orbit</em> – and share findings.
Meeting and getting to know different contributors, actors and visitors as well as investigating contemporary fields of interests, issues and questions is essential in this regard.</p>

<p>If you ask me about the success of this particular trip, I don&rsquo;t have a tool to measure that (just yet). What I do have are a growing number of strategies that indicate how to best approach the SpaceTraveler&rsquo;s mission. One of them I learned from philosopher, writer and designer John Thackara and his talk <a href="http://www.doorsofperception.com/learning-institutions/presence-and-encounter-how-we-meet-is-as-important-as-why/">How we meet is as important as why</a>. The following paragraph is taken from his write-up: </br></p>

<p>&ldquo;In his book I and Thou in 1923, the philosopher and theologian Martin Buber counseled that &lsquo;All knowledge is dialogic&rsquo;  – but he did not just advocate talk. Community and connection are not just about words, he said;  they’re about encounter, and presence.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A thought that does not only justify, but strongly recommends we cross an ocean – or possibly an entire galaxy – in order to meet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.2 - *thdwuuf]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/07/thdwuuf/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-07T10:51:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/07/07/thdwuuf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kon’nichi wa and welcome from the Ruby Orbit.</br>
By the by, *thdwuuf is an Onomatopoeia – a written sound – that describes the noise any kind of boots creates when walking on sand.</p>

<p>Running through my mission checklist it says: Leave a visible trace!</br>
In this regard, you may have noticed the shiny red element greeting you at the top of my Logbook.
It resembles the imprint of my boots:</p>

<p><img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/velement/bootsteps.png" alt="SpaceTraveler" width="200" height="200"></p>

<p>Neat, right?
The soles sport a pattern made from gemstones of different shapes and sizes – proper RubyBoots!</br>
Wherever Ruby gravity takes me, these prints will be left in space. In this way you are able to track my projects or undertakings and instantly know they are part of this SpaceTraveler Mission.</p>

<p>Why bootsteps? I was inspired by the following historic event: </br>
the Apollo 11 spaceflight. More precisely the trace Neil Armstrong left behind on the Moon on July 21 at 02:56 UTC.</p>

<p><img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/velement/261252main_21_firstfootprint_946-710.jpg" alt="Footprints on the moon"></br>
<a href="http://www.nasa.gov/50th/favpic/moonFootprint.html">Image Source</a></p>

<p>Following I&rsquo;m going to take you on a visual stroll throught the early development of this visual element as well as its iterations.</p>

<p><img src="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/images/velement/element_dev_down.jpg" alt="Element development" height="700"></br></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0.0.0.1 - Navigating the Curious Ruby Orbit.]]></title>
    <link href="http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/06/11/navigating-the-curious-ruby-orbit/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-11T13:35:15+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://logbook.spacetraveler.io/logbook/2015/06/11/navigating-the-curious-ruby-orbit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This space tells of a particular community that evolved from gravity, more precisely <i>Ruby Gravity</i>. According to the SpaceTraveler’s Encyclopedia Ruby Gravity is defined as a natural phenomenon by which all those who affiliate with the Ruby programming language meet one another. Beware, it may result in spirited conversations, fruitful collaboration and sometimes genuine friendships.</p>

<p>The SpaceTraveler drifts through the well-known as well as peripheral edges of this community, to find essential and/ or creative applications of the language, while purposely leaving a visible trace.
As with most stories, this adventure too begins with one small step *thdwuuf</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
